[
    {
        "id": 1,
        "topic": "Mechanics",
        "question": "A 2 kg ball is thrown upwards with an initial velocity of 20 m/s from ground level. What is the total energy of the system when the ball reaches its maximum height?",
        "options": [
            "A)10J",
            "B)20J",
            "C)100J",
            "D)200J"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "C",
        "solution": ""
    },
    {
        "id": 2,
        "topic": "Mechanics",
        "question": "A 5 kg object is initially at rest on the ground. It is then lifted vertically to a height of 20 meters and acquires a velocity of 3 m/s at that position. What is the change in the object's total mechanical energy during this process?",
        "options": [
            "A)14.5J",
            "B)104.5J",
            "C)1004.5J",
            "D)981J"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "C",
        "solution": ""
    },
    {
        "id": 3,
        "topic": "Mechanics",
        "question": "A book rests on a table. Which of the following statements correctly describes an action-reaction pair involving the book?",
        "options": [
            "A) The Earth’s gravity pulls the book downward , and the table pushes the book upward",
            "B)The book exerts a downward force on the table, and the table exerts an upward force on the book",
            "C)The book pushes the table , and air resistance pushes back on the book",
            "D)The table supports the book , and the book’s mass creates friction"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "B）The book exerts a downward force on the table, and the table exerts an upward force on the book",
        "solution": "A:The reaction to Earth’s gravity is the book pulling up on the Earth, not the table’s normal force. C:Air resistance is unrelated to the book-table interaction D:The table’s force and friction are unrelated Third Law pairs."
    },
    {
        "id": 4,
        "topic": "Mechanics",
        "question": "A rubber ball strikes a wall and bounces back. Which of the following statements is/are correct?",
        "options": [
            "A) The total momentum of the ball and the wall is conserved.",
            "B) The momentum of the ball is conserved.",
            "C) The momentum of the wall is conserved.",
            "D) None of the above."
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "A The total momentum of the ball and the wall is conserved.",
        "solution": "A:Momentum is always conserved in a system if no external forces act. The ball-wall system is isolated during the collision, so their total momentum remains unchanged"
    },
    {
        "id": 5,
        "topic": "Mechanics",
        "question": "A uniform 4-meter-long beam of negligible weight is balanced at its pivot. A 6 kg mass is placed 1 meter to the left of the pivot. What mass must be placed 2 meters to the right of the pivot to keep the beam in equilibrium?",
        "options": [
            "A) 1.5 kg",
            "B) 3 kg",
            "C) 4.5 kg",
            "D) 6 kg"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "B3kg",
        "solution": ""
    },
    {
        "id": 6,
        "topic": "Mechanics",
        "question": "A motorcyclist traveling at 90 km/h on a straight road suddenly notices a traffic signal 75 meters ahead turning red. If the rider's reaction time is 0.4 seconds, what is the minimum deceleration required to stop safely before the signal?",
        "options": [
            "A) 3.15 m s⁻²",
            "B) 3.82 m s⁻²",
            "C) 4.25 m s⁻²",
            "D) 4.81 m s⁻²"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "D4.81 m s⁻²",
        "solution": "25* 0.4 =10m      75-10=65m 0=25^2 + 2a(65),    a= -4.81m s⁻²"
    },
    {
        "id": 7,
        "topic": "Mechanics",
        "question": "An object at rest will remain at rest unless acted upon by:",
        "options": [
            "A) A net force",
            "B) Gravity",
            "C) Friction",
            "D) An external agent"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "(Anet force",
        "solution": ""
    },
    {
        "id": 8,
        "topic": "Mechanics",
        "question": "According to Newton's second law, the acceleration of an object is directly proportional to the net force acting on it and inversely proportional to its:",
        "options": [
            "A) Mass",
            "B) Velocity",
            "C) Temperature",
            "D) Distance"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "(A Mass",
        "solution": ""
    },
    {
        "id": 9,
        "topic": "Mechanics",
        "question": "When a person pushes against a wall, the wall pushes back with an equal and opposite force. This demonstrates which law?",
        "options": [
            "A) First Law",
            "B) Second Law",
            "C) Third Law",
            "D) Law of Conservation of Momentum"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "(C Third Law",
        "solution": ""
    },
    {
        "id": 10,
        "topic": "Mechanics",
        "question": "Which of the following is not a vector?",
        "options": [
            "A) Velocity",
            "B) Force",
            "C) Momentum",
            "D) Speed"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "D",
        "solution": ""
    },
    {
        "id": 2,
        "topic": "Mechanics",
        "question": "i) Velocity\tii)  Initial speed\tiii) Final speed\tiv) Mass",
        "options": [
            "A) ii,iii",
            "B) i, iv",
            "C) i,ii,iii",
            "D) ii,iii,iv"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "B",
        "solution": ""
    },
    {
        "id": 11,
        "topic": "Mechanics",
        "question": "A force of 36 N is applied to a 999 g object. What is the acceleration of the object?",
        "options": [
            "A)  0.36m/s²",
            "B) 36.0 m/s²",
            "C) 27.8 m/s²",
            "D) 2.78 m/s²"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "B",
        "solution": ""
    },
    {
        "id": 12,
        "topic": "Mechanics",
        "question": "An object is moving at 25 m/s and comes to a stop in 5 seconds. What is the average acceleration?",
        "options": [
            "A) -5 m/s²",
            "B) -10 m/s²",
            "C) 10 m/s²",
            "D) 5 m/s²"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "A",
        "solution": ""
    },
    {
        "id": 13,
        "topic": "Mechanics",
        "question": "If a 0.0865 kg object is acted upon by a net force of  3N, what will be its acceleration?",
        "options": [
            "A) 34.6 m/s²",
            "B) 84.0 m/s²",
            "C) 29.9 m/s²",
            "D) 28.4 m/s²"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "A",
        "solution": ""
    },
    {
        "id": 14,
        "topic": "Mechanics",
        "question": "A car accelerates from rest to  0.07 km/s in 2 seconds. What is the acceleration of the car?",
        "options": [
            "A) 30 m/s²",
            "B) 33 m/s²",
            "C) 35 m/s²",
            "D) 39 m/s²"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "C",
        "solution": ""
    },
    {
        "id": 15,
        "topic": "Mechanics",
        "question": "If a 20 kg object is pushed with a force of 80 N, what is its acceleration?",
        "options": [
            "A) 2 m/s²",
            "B) 3 m/s²",
            "C) 4 m/s²",
            "D) 5 m/s²"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "C",
        "solution": ""
    },
    {
        "id": 16,
        "topic": "Mechanics",
        "question": "An object is thrown upward with an initial velocity of 20 m/s. How high will it rise before coming to a stop?",
        "options": [
            "A) 10 m",
            "B) 20 m",
            "C) 30 m",
            "D) 40 m"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "B",
        "solution": ""
    },
    {
        "id": 17,
        "topic": "Mechanics",
        "question": "A 5 kg object is sliding on a frictionless surface with a speed of 10 m/s. What is its momentum?",
        "options": [
            "A) 10 kg·m/s",
            "B) 25 kg·m/s",
            "C) 50 kg·m/s",
            "D) 100 kg·m/s"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "C",
        "solution": ""
    },
    {
        "id": 18,
        "topic": "Mechanics",
        "question": "What is the net force acting on a 4 kg object that is accelerating at 3 m/s²?",
        "options": [
            "A) 4 N",
            "B) 12 N",
            "C) 16 N",
            "D) 20 N"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "B",
        "solution": ""
    },
    {
        "id": 19,
        "topic": "Mechanics",
        "question": "Which of the following changes will lead to a decrease in pressure, assuming the amount of gas remains the same?",
        "options": [
            "A) Increasing the volume while keeping temperature constant.",
            "B) Decreasing the volume while keeping temperature constant.",
            "C) Increasing the temperature while keeping volume constant.",
            "D) Adding more gas to the system at constant volume and temperature."
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "A",
        "solution": ""
    },
    {
        "id": 20,
        "topic": "Mechanics",
        "question": "What happens to the pressure of a gas if its volume is halved while temperature remains constant?",
        "options": [
            "A)Pressure doubles",
            "B)Pressure halves",
            "C)Pressure remains the same",
            "D)Pressure quadruples"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "A",
        "solution": ""
    },
    {
        "id": 3,
        "topic": "Mechanics",
        "question": "When ball B touch the ground, ball A is above ball B. 2 balls will never meet",
        "options": [
            "A)(1)",
            "B)(2)",
            "C)(1),(2)",
            "D)None of the above"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "A",
        "solution": ""
    },
    {
        "id": 21,
        "topic": "Mechanics",
        "question": "Assume no friction.When a man stands on the Earth, push the box forward with his hand, what will happen?",
        "options": [
            "A)The box move forward",
            "B)The box move backward",
            "C)The box move upward",
            "D)None of the above"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "D",
        "solution": ""
    },
    {
        "id": 22,
        "topic": "Mechanics",
        "question": "Assume no friction and have air resistance.When a man stands on the Earth, pushes the box forward with his hand, what will happen?",
        "options": [
            "A)The box move forward",
            "B)The box move backward",
            "C)The box move upward",
            "D)None of the above"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "A",
        "solution": ""
    },
    {
        "id": 23,
        "topic": "Mechanics",
        "question": "When you are scrolling reels/shorts/tick tock, if you push your finger from bottom to top of the screen, what will happen?Assume no friction.",
        "options": [
            "A)You watch the next reel",
            "B)You watch the last reel",
            "C)You stay in the reel you are watching",
            "D)none of the above"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "A",
        "solution": ""
    },
    {
        "id": 24,
        "topic": "Mechanics",
        "question": "When you are scrolling reels/shorts/tick tock, if you push your finger from bottom to top of the screen on an iPhone 4, what will happen?Assume no friction.",
        "options": [
            "A)You watch the next reel",
            "B)You watch the last reel",
            "C)You stay in the reel you are watching",
            "D)none of the above"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "C",
        "solution": ""
    },
    {
        "id": 25,
        "topic": "Mechanics",
        "question": "Marcy pulls a backpack on wheels down the 100m hall. The 60N force is applied at an angle of 30° above the horizontal. How much work is done by Marcy?",
        "options": [
            "A)3800",
            "B)5200",
            "C)1500",
            "D)4300"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "B",
        "solution": ""
    },
    {
        "id": 26,
        "topic": "Mechanics",
        "question": "A 30,000-kg freight car is coasting at 0.850 m/s and it crashed with a 10,000 kg train .  What is the final velocity of the freight car?",
        "options": [
            "A)1.3",
            "B)0",
            "C)0.396",
            "D)0.182"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "D",
        "solution": ""
    },
    {
        "id": 27,
        "topic": "Mechanics",
        "question": "What is the velocity of a 900-kg car initially moving at 30.0 m/s, just after it hits a 150-kg deer initially running at 12.0 m/s in the same direction? Assume the deer remains in the car.",
        "options": [
            "A)30",
            "B)27.4",
            "C)32.1",
            "D)24.6"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "B",
        "solution": ""
    },
    {
        "id": 28,
        "topic": "Mechanics",
        "question": "A tennis ball is struck such that it leaves the racket horizontally with a speed of 28.0 m/s. The ball hits the court at a horizontal distance of 19.6 m from the racket. What is the vertical height of the tennis ball when it leaves the racket?",
        "options": [
            "A)2.2",
            "B)1.7",
            "C)2.4",
            "D)3.4"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "C",
        "solution": "0.5x9.81x0.7^(2)"
    },
    {
        "id": 29,
        "topic": "Mechanics",
        "question": "A nurse pushes a cart by exerting a force on the handle at a downward angle 35.0° below the horizontal. The loaded cart has a mass of 28.0 kg, and the force of friction is 60.0 N.What force must the nurse exert to move at a constant velocity?",
        "options": [
            "A)76",
            "B)73",
            "C)34",
            "D)80"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "B",
        "solution": ""
    },
    {
        "id": 30,
        "topic": "Mechanics",
        "question": "When an object is projected vertically upwards, its velocity is ___ at the highest point.",
        "options": [
            "A)same as start",
            "B)zero",
            "C)increased",
            "D)decreased"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "B",
        "solution": ""
    },
    {
        "id": 2,
        "topic": "Mechanics",
        "question": "i)backwards ii)forwards iii)downwards",
        "options": [
            "A)ii only",
            "B)i and iii only",
            "C)ii and iii only",
            "D)all of the above"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "A",
        "solution": ""
    },
    {
        "id": 31,
        "topic": "Mechanics",
        "question": "Which of the following statements is true about Newton’s FIRST Law?",
        "options": [
            "A) An object at rest remains at rest unless there is an unbalanced force acting on it.",
            "B) The net force acting on an object is equal to its mass times its acceleration.",
            "C) For every action, there is an equal and opposite reaction.",
            "D) Mr Man is very cute."
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "A",
        "solution": ""
    },
    {
        "id": 32,
        "topic": "Mechanics",
        "question": "Mr Man and Mr Hung both run from A to B. Mr Man has an average speed of 1ms-1 and Mr Hung has an average speed of 2ms-1. Which of the following must be true?",
        "options": [
            "A) The magnitude of Mr Hung’s average velocity is higher than the magnitude of Mr Man’s average velocity.",
            "B) If they start at A at the same time, Mr Hung will reach B first.",
            "C) The displacement of Mr Man is the same as the displacement of Mr Hung.",
            "D) None of the above"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "C",
        "solution": ""
    },
    {
        "id": 33,
        "topic": "Mechanics",
        "question": "Box A of mass 30kg and Box B of mass 3kg were released from rest in vacuum. Which box will reach the ground first?",
        "options": [
            "A) Box A",
            "B) Box B",
            "C) They reach the ground at the same time",
            "D) Cannot determine"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "C",
        "solution": ""
    }
]